# **Stephanie Pennington**

9404 Kinnerton Place Frederick, MD 21704 T: (301) 606-3322

October 29, 2019

Job ID: 310001 Earth Scientist

Joint Global Change Research Institute 5825 University Research Court College Park, MD 20740

Dear Dr. Ben Bond-Lamberty,

I am writing to express my interest in the Earth Science position at the Joint Global Change Research Institute (JGCRI). I have three years of experience working with environmental data collected from ecological and paleoclimate research projects and believe I would be a valuable contribution to the PREMIS initiative.

As a post-bachelor research associate, my primary role is to maintain the field site at the Smithsonian Environmental Research Center (SERC) and facilitate data download, processing, and visualization for senior scientists. To ensure data integrity, I have developed a pipeline of coding scripts using R to parse raw data from a variety of formats into user-friendly data frames for further analysis. I also maintain multiple repositories on Github which contain documentation, raw data, and version-controlled code. In addition to my primary tasks, I have taken leadership roles in manuscript writing, field installations, and mentorship.

Enclosed is my resume which highlights my technical and leadership skills, making me an exceptional candidate for this position. Thank you for your consideration and I look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerely, Stephanie Pennington

Stephanie Pennington

stephanie.pennington@pnnl.gov

# **Stephanie Pennington**

stephanie.pennington@pnnl.gov (301) 606-3322

#### **EDUCATION**

## 2013 - 2017 Bachelor of Science, Atmospheric and Oceanic Science

University of Maryland, College Park, Maryland Recipient: Tannenbaum Prize in Climate Science

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 2018 - present Post Bachelor Research Associate

Pacific Northwest National Laboratory

Conduct field work and data corresondence to PIs and collaborators across the US, lead field installations, QA/QC and data processing/visualization, and manuscrip writing for an initiative focusing on the terrestrial-aquatic interface

• Co-mentored a student through a 10-week research project and report

### 2017 - 2018 Faculty Research Assistant

University of Maryland, Department of Geology

Coded scripts in R language to process and reformat model AMOC pseudo-proxy data to represent bioturbation of marine sediments and sample resolution at several collection sites.

### **2016 - 2017** Undergraduate Student Researcher

Pacific Northwest National Laboratory

Collected and analyzed CESM1-BGC ocean data, as NetCDF files in R, to identify intermediate water in the South Pacific to track changes under radiative forcing scenarios.

### **SKILLS**

**Software and Coding** | R, C, CDO (climate data operators), RStudio, Git/Github, LoggerNet, HOBOware

Statistical and Computational Methods | Data DA/QV, visualization, smoothing, regression analysis

**Technical** | Proficient in LI-COR, Campbell, Onset HOBO, and METER environmental monitoring systems. Experience in electrical wiring, installation of Granier-style sap flux sensors

### MENTORSHIP AND TEACHING

"R Basics Workshop" | Conducted a 10-week R basics workshop for SULI and high school student interns

"Rmarkdown Workshop for Reproducible Research" | *Presentation, University of Delaware and Virginia Commonwealth University*